<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-05T08:29:42-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/feed.xml</id><title type="html">NASA Transform to Open Science</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><author><name>TOPS</name></author><entry><title type="html">2023: Year of Open Science</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/year-of-open-science/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023: Year of Open Science" /><published>2023-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/year-of-open-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/year-of-open-science/">&lt;p&gt;2023: A Year of Open Science!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 11 January 2023 the US White House - joined by 10 federal agencies, a coalition of more than 85 universities, and other organizations — declared 2023 to be a Year of Open Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White House &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2023/01/11/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-new-actions-to-advance-open-and-equitable-research/&quot;&gt;factsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NASA announces a Year of Open Science in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-00019-y&quot;&gt;Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Federal &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.science.gov/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NSF releases a Year of Open Science &lt;a href=&quot;https://nsf.widencollective.com/portals/sd9nlyvd/YearofOpenScienceToolkit&quot;&gt;Toolbox&lt;/a&gt; including powerpoint templates, letterhead, poster, and virtual backgrounds!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year will celebrate the benefits and successes of open science and inspire more scientists to adopt open science. Ultimately, the success of the Year of Open Science will be driven by collaborations with individuals, teams, and organizations who are ready to transform the culture of science into one that celebrates openness, and inclusion!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Year of Open Science has set out 4 goals to work towards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish strategic approaches for advancing open science&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Promote equitable participation in open science through transparency, integrity and equity of reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Account for open science activities in evaluations and incentives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engage underrepresented communities in the advancement of open science and research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-us&quot;&gt;Join Us!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sign up your organization and be listed below, please fill out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/KPKaejc2WP7dm5XVA&quot;&gt;form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;participating-organizations&quot;&gt;Participating organizations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/ASAP.html&quot;&gt;Aligning Science Across Parkinson’s (ASAP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/ASAPbio.html&quot;&gt;ASAPbio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/COS.html&quot;&gt;Center for Open Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/CTF.html&quot;&gt;Children’s Tumor Foundation (CTF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/GOSH.html&quot;&gt;Gathering for Open Science Hardware (GOSH)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/HRA.html&quot;&gt;Health Research Alliance (HRA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/HELIOS.html&quot;&gt;Higher Education Leadership Initiative for Open Scholarship (HELIOS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/LSEF.html&quot;&gt;Life Sciences Editors Foundation (LSEF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/PREreview.html&quot;&gt;PREreview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/ORFG.html&quot;&gt;Open Research Funders Group (ORFG)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/CreativeCommons.html&quot;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/SPARC.html&quot;&gt;Scholarly Publishing and Academic Resources Coalition (SPARC)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/MJFoxFoundation.html&quot;&gt;The Michael J. Fox Foundation for Parkinson’s Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/GOFAIRUS.html&quot;&gt;GO FAIR US&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/SpringerNature.html&quot;&gt;Springer Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/STM.html&quot;&gt;STM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/FAS.html&quot;&gt;Federation of American Scientists (FAS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/WilsonCenter.html&quot;&gt;The Wilson Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/Frontiers.html&quot;&gt;Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/IOI.html&quot;&gt;Invest in Open Infrastructure (IOI)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/FASEB.html&quot;&gt;Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology (FASEB)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Year_of_Open_Science_Guide/participants/Elsevier.html&quot;&gt;Elsevier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-you&quot;&gt;For You&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you just beginning your open science journey? Perhaps you have only just begun to post your code or data online, share your pre-prints, or share your null hypothesis as part of your grant application? Or perhaps you are exploring science communication on a personal blog. All of these behaviors exemplify open science and we would like for you to join us in the Year of Open Science!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are excited to learn and encourage others to learn about open science as part of the Year of Open Science, then we invite you to explore how to take &lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Open_Science_Cookbook/Your_Open_Science_Journey.html#section-3-open-science-at-work&quot;&gt;Individual Actions for the Year of Open Science&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-your-team&quot;&gt;For Your Team&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your team interested in adopting open science principles and practices, but unsure of how to begin? The Year of Open Science team activities could help you reflect together on how to equip the people at your organization with practical knowledge in open science, as well as introduce them to a wider community of open science practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn how to get your team involved in &lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Open_Science_Cookbook/Your_Teams_Open_Science_Journey.html#section-1-engage-with-open-science&quot;&gt;Team Actions for the Year of Open Science&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-your-entire-organization&quot;&gt;For Your Entire Organization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your organization is ready to devote people, funds, and other resources to adopting open science throughout the organization. If your leaders are committed to becoming known as an open science organization, and excited to facilitate open science research through its policy and actions, then we invite you to explore &lt;a href=&quot;https://nasa.github.io/Transform-to-Open-Science-Book/Open_Science_Cookbook/Your_Organizations_Open_Science_Journey.html&quot;&gt;Organization Actions for the Year of Open Science&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TOPS</name></author><summary type="html">2023: A Year of Open Science! On 11 January 2023 the US White House - joined by 10 federal agencies, a coalition of more than 85 universities, and other organizations — declared 2023 to be a Year of Open Science. White House factsheet NASA announces a Year of Open Science in Nature Federal website NSF releases a Year of Open Science Toolbox including powerpoint templates, letterhead, poster, and virtual backgrounds! This year will celebrate the benefits and successes of open science and inspire more scientists to adopt open science. Ultimately, the success of the Year of Open Science will be driven by collaborations with individuals, teams, and organizations who are ready to transform the culture of science into one that celebrates openness, and inclusion! A Year of Open Science has set out 4 goals to work towards: Establish strategic approaches for advancing open science Promote equitable participation in open science through transparency, integrity and equity of reviews. Account for open science activities in evaluations and incentives Engage underrepresented communities in the advancement of open science and research Join Us! To sign up your organization and be listed below, please fill out this form. Participating organizations Aligning Science Across Parkinson’s (ASAP) ASAPbio Center for Open Science Children’s Tumor Foundation (CTF) Gathering for Open Science Hardware (GOSH) Health Research Alliance (HRA) Higher Education Leadership Initiative for Open Scholarship (HELIOS) Life Sciences Editors Foundation (LSEF) PREreview Open Research Funders Group (ORFG) Creative Commons Scholarly Publishing and Academic Resources Coalition (SPARC) The Michael J. Fox Foundation for Parkinson’s Research GO FAIR US Springer Nature STM Federation of American Scientists (FAS) The Wilson Center Frontiers Invest in Open Infrastructure (IOI) Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology (FASEB) Elsevier For You Are you just beginning your open science journey? Perhaps you have only just begun to post your code or data online, share your pre-prints, or share your null hypothesis as part of your grant application? Or perhaps you are exploring science communication on a personal blog. All of these behaviors exemplify open science and we would like for you to join us in the Year of Open Science! If you are excited to learn and encourage others to learn about open science as part of the Year of Open Science, then we invite you to explore how to take Individual Actions for the Year of Open Science! For Your Team Is your team interested in adopting open science principles and practices, but unsure of how to begin? The Year of Open Science team activities could help you reflect together on how to equip the people at your organization with practical knowledge in open science, as well as introduce them to a wider community of open science practitioners. Learn how to get your team involved in Team Actions for the Year of Open Science! For Your Entire Organization Is your organization is ready to devote people, funds, and other resources to adopting open science throughout the organization. If your leaders are committed to becoming known as an open science organization, and excited to facilitate open science research through its policy and actions, then we invite you to explore Organization Actions for the Year of Open Science!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/post_1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/post_1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Science 101</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/open-science-101/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Science 101" /><published>2023-10-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/open-science-101</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/open-science-101/">&lt;p&gt;TOPS aims to meet everyone where they are at on their open science journey. While some members of our growing community may have practiced open science for many years, others may be trying to transition to a new way of conducting research or are students who are looking to begin their scientific careers. As such, TOPS’ first priority is to develop the infrastructure to train 20,000 scientists and researchers as part of our five-year program. This community-developed open science curriculum will introduce those beginning their open science journey to important definitions, tools, and resources; and provide participants at all levels recommendations on best practices from subject matter experts. TOPS will initially focus on developing the Open Science 101, designed as five modules that mimic a scientific workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the 2023 Year of Open Science, TOPS is developing strategic partnerships with scientific associations to teach open science during large annual meetings, special science team summer schools, and other events. The vision for the Open Science 101 and other learning resources is for a CC-BY licensed online, open course, hosted on the OpenEDx platform, that can be used to train scientists and award NASA open science badges.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TOPS</name></author><summary type="html">TOPS aims to meet everyone where they are at on their open science journey. While some members of our growing community may have practiced open science for many years, others may be trying to transition to a new way of conducting research or are students who are looking to begin their scientific careers. As such, TOPS’ first priority is to develop the infrastructure to train 20,000 scientists and researchers as part of our five-year program. This community-developed open science curriculum will introduce those beginning their open science journey to important definitions, tools, and resources; and provide participants at all levels recommendations on best practices from subject matter experts. TOPS will initially focus on developing the Open Science 101, designed as five modules that mimic a scientific workflow. For the 2023 Year of Open Science, TOPS is developing strategic partnerships with scientific associations to teach open science during large annual meetings, special science team summer schools, and other events. The vision for the Open Science 101 and other learning resources is for a CC-BY licensed online, open course, hosted on the OpenEDx platform, that can be used to train scientists and award NASA open science badges.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/youngscientists.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/youngscientists.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Science Analysis Working Groups: Collaborating on the Future</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/open-science-analysis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Science Analysis Working Groups: Collaborating on the Future" /><published>2023-09-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/open-science-analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/open-science-analysis/">&lt;p&gt;It’s a closely held belief among those who practice open science that it can lead to wonderful discoveries and collaborations that can close the gap between the now and the future of science. For some in the open science community, those collaborative opportunities can take them down a path they never expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in his career in medical sciences at the University of South Carolina, Dr. Willian da Silveira jumped at the opportunity to work with NASA through a funding grant. After everything was settled and work started, he was added to an email list where he saw GeneLab, NASA’s space-biology database, which is now a part of the Open Science Data Repository, promoting their Analysis Working Groups.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TOPS</name></author><summary type="html">It’s a closely held belief among those who practice open science that it can lead to wonderful discoveries and collaborations that can close the gap between the now and the future of science. For some in the open science community, those collaborative opportunities can take them down a path they never expected. Early in his career in medical sciences at the University of South Carolina, Dr. Willian da Silveira jumped at the opportunity to work with NASA through a funding grant. After everything was settled and work started, he was added to an email list where he saw GeneLab, NASA’s space-biology database, which is now a part of the Open Science Data Repository, promoting their Analysis Working Groups.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/williansilveira.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/williansilveira.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NEON: Combining Open Science and Wildfire Studies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/neon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NEON: Combining Open Science and Wildfire Studies" /><published>2023-09-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/neon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/neon/">&lt;p&gt;At the University of Colorado Boulder, a Fire Ecologist by the name of Dr. Jennifer Balch is studying how forests recover after wildfires and how they contribute to atmospheric carbon levels – work that is vital to climate change studies and could ultimately create more accurate models of forest fire carbon release for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When forests burn, the massive quantities of carbon stored within the vegetation is rapidly released into the atmosphere. As forests recover, trees and undergrowth mature and gradually re-absorb carbon, storing it away once again. With carbon being one of the dreaded greenhouse gases, this topic is becoming increasingly relevant to our warming planet and is being facilitated by the efforts of the open science community.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TOPS</name></author><summary type="html">At the University of Colorado Boulder, a Fire Ecologist by the name of Dr. Jennifer Balch is studying how forests recover after wildfires and how they contribute to atmospheric carbon levels – work that is vital to climate change studies and could ultimately create more accurate models of forest fire carbon release for future studies. When forests burn, the massive quantities of carbon stored within the vegetation is rapidly released into the atmosphere. As forests recover, trees and undergrowth mature and gradually re-absorb carbon, storing it away once again. With carbon being one of the dreaded greenhouse gases, this topic is becoming increasingly relevant to our warming planet and is being facilitated by the efforts of the open science community.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/neon.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/neon.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Xarray: Empowering Scientific Data Analysis within the NASA community</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/xarray/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Xarray: Empowering Scientific Data Analysis within the NASA community" /><published>2023-08-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-08-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/xarray</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/xarray/">&lt;p&gt;Xarray is an open-source Python package that makes working with complex, multi-dimensional arrays elegant, intuitive, and efficient. Real-world datasets, such as those generated by NASA, are often a collection of many related variables on a common grid. These datasets are more than just arrays of values: they have labels which describe how array values map to locations in dimensions such as space and time and metadata that describes how the data was collected and processed. Xarray embraces the complexity of real-world datasets and enables users to use metadata such as dimension names and coordinate labels to easily analyze, manipulate, and visualize their datasets. Xarray makes data analysis more intuitive and enjoyable, while describing how data was collected and processed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TOPS</name></author><summary type="html">Xarray is an open-source Python package that makes working with complex, multi-dimensional arrays elegant, intuitive, and efficient. Real-world datasets, such as those generated by NASA, are often a collection of many related variables on a common grid. These datasets are more than just arrays of values: they have labels which describe how array values map to locations in dimensions such as space and time and metadata that describes how the data was collected and processed. Xarray embraces the complexity of real-world datasets and enables users to use metadata such as dimension names and coordinate labels to easily analyze, manipulate, and visualize their datasets. Xarray makes data analysis more intuitive and enjoyable, while describing how data was collected and processed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/xarray.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/xarray.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Success Stories of Open Science Series: With a large network of people, you can do a lot of fun things in science: Q&amp;amp;A with Dr. Afshin Beheshti on open science practices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/afshinbeheshti/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success Stories of Open Science Series: With a large network of people, you can do a lot of fun things in science: Q&amp;amp;A with Dr. Afshin Beheshti on open science practices" /><published>2023-07-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-07-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/afshinbeheshti</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/afshinbeheshti/">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Afshin Beheshti is a bioinformatician and principal investigator at KBR at NASA’s Ames Research Center. With a background in physics, he works on space biology projects related to microRNA (miRNA) and mitochondrial changes. However, he refuses to be a one-dimensional researcher, whichled him to work on various topics including COVID-19/SARS-CoV-2, cancer, high altitude impact on biology, and traumatic brain injury. He leads the Multi-Omics Analysis Working Group (AWG) at NASA’s Gene Lab, where everyone collaborates to develop guidelines and ways to process and analyze Big Data. Through this model, his team discovered that mitochondrial dysfunction, when the mitochondria do not work as well as they should, is a key biological issue during spaceflight. In addition, he is the president of a nonprofit called COVID-19 International Research Team (COV-IRT).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TOPS</name></author><summary type="html">Dr. Afshin Beheshti is a bioinformatician and principal investigator at KBR at NASA’s Ames Research Center. With a background in physics, he works on space biology projects related to microRNA (miRNA) and mitochondrial changes. However, he refuses to be a one-dimensional researcher, whichled him to work on various topics including COVID-19/SARS-CoV-2, cancer, high altitude impact on biology, and traumatic brain injury. He leads the Multi-Omics Analysis Working Group (AWG) at NASA’s Gene Lab, where everyone collaborates to develop guidelines and ways to process and analyze Big Data. Through this model, his team discovered that mitochondrial dysfunction, when the mitochondria do not work as well as they should, is a key biological issue during spaceflight. In addition, he is the president of a nonprofit called COVID-19 International Research Team (COV-IRT).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/afshin.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/afshin.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Success Stories of Open Science Series: Q&amp;amp;A with Dr. Leo Singer on open science practices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/leosinger/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success Stories of Open Science Series: Q&amp;amp;A with Dr. Leo Singer on open science practices" /><published>2023-07-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-07-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/leosinger</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/leosinger/">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Leo Singer has been a research astrophysicist at NASA’s Goddard Space Flight Center since 2015, working on the General Coordinates Network(GCN)—NASA’s next-generation time domain and multi messenger astronomy alert system. With a background in gravitational waves, his research projects concern ground-based optical telescopes and multi wavelength follow-up. He also works on real-time analysis of the Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory (LIGO) data, signal processing, Bayesian inference, and synoptic optical transient surveys. He is actively participating in the Astropy Project, a community effort to develop Python packages for astronomy. He co-authored and co-maintains LIGO’s open source public alerts pipeline and science outreach material for astronomers, the LIGO/Virgo/KAGRA Public Alerts User Guide.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TOPS</name></author><summary type="html">Dr. Leo Singer has been a research astrophysicist at NASA’s Goddard Space Flight Center since 2015, working on the General Coordinates Network(GCN)—NASA’s next-generation time domain and multi messenger astronomy alert system. With a background in gravitational waves, his research projects concern ground-based optical telescopes and multi wavelength follow-up. He also works on real-time analysis of the Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory (LIGO) data, signal processing, Bayesian inference, and synoptic optical transient surveys. He is actively participating in the Astropy Project, a community effort to develop Python packages for astronomy. He co-authored and co-maintains LIGO’s open source public alerts pipeline and science outreach material for astronomers, the LIGO/Virgo/KAGRA Public Alerts User Guide.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/leosinger.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/leosinger.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Success Stories of Open Science Series: Equitable science for all: Q&amp;amp;A with Dr. Flavio Azevedo on open science practices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/flavioazevedo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success Stories of Open Science Series: Equitable science for all: Q&amp;amp;A with Dr. Flavio Azevedo on open science practices" /><published>2023-07-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-07-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/flavioazevedo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/flavioazevedo/">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Flavio Azevedo is a political psychologist and an associate researcher at the University of Cambridge. Primarily, his research investigates the role of ideology and identity in supporting policies that perpetuate social andeconomic injustices. Having come from a low socioeconomic status in Brazil, he fell in love with the promise of academia as a great equalizer. This passion has led him to co-found and direct the Framework for Open and Reproducible Research Training (FORRT), an award-winning interdisciplinary community of almost 500 early-career scholars, aiming to integrate open scholarship principles into higher education and advance research transparency, reproducibility, rigor, and ethics through pedagogical reform and meta-science. In addition, he is participating in the NASA TOPS’ effort to build the ScienceCore curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TOPS</name></author><summary type="html">Dr. Flavio Azevedo is a political psychologist and an associate researcher at the University of Cambridge. Primarily, his research investigates the role of ideology and identity in supporting policies that perpetuate social andeconomic injustices. Having come from a low socioeconomic status in Brazil, he fell in love with the promise of academia as a great equalizer. This passion has led him to co-found and direct the Framework for Open and Reproducible Research Training (FORRT), an award-winning interdisciplinary community of almost 500 early-career scholars, aiming to integrate open scholarship principles into higher education and advance research transparency, reproducibility, rigor, and ethics through pedagogical reform and meta-science. In addition, he is participating in the NASA TOPS’ effort to build the ScienceCore curriculum.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/azevedo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/azevedo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Success Stories of Open Science Series: Learn by doing transparent, replicable, and understandable science: Q&amp;amp;A with Africa Ixmucane Flores-Anderson on open science practices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/africaflores-anderson/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success Stories of Open Science Series: Learn by doing transparent, replicable, and understandable science: Q&amp;amp;A with Africa Ixmucane Flores-Anderson on open science practices" /><published>2023-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/africaflores-anderson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/africaflores-anderson/">&lt;p&gt;Originally from Guatemala, Africa Ixmucane Flores-Anderson is a research scientist at the University of Alabama in Huntsville who has been working with satellite data for over 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, she works with SERVIR Global—a joint initiative between NASA and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID)—as the Land Cover Land Use Change (LCLUC) and Ecosystems Theme Lead. She focuses on using optical and synthetic aperture radar (SAR) satellite datasets for environmental monitoring, including but not limited to 1) water quality of freshwater bodies, 2) forest disturbances, and 3) LCLUC. She also serves as an Envoy of the NASA-Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) InSAR (NISAR) mission, and she led the creation of the joint SERVIR-SilvaCarbon SAR Handbook on how to use SAR for forest monitoring and ecosystem applications. She is also a Ph.D. candidate in natural resource sciences at McGill University, specializing in SAR applications to improve forest monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TOPS</name></author><summary type="html">Originally from Guatemala, Africa Ixmucane Flores-Anderson is a research scientist at the University of Alabama in Huntsville who has been working with satellite data for over 15 years. Currently, she works with SERVIR Global—a joint initiative between NASA and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID)—as the Land Cover Land Use Change (LCLUC) and Ecosystems Theme Lead. She focuses on using optical and synthetic aperture radar (SAR) satellite datasets for environmental monitoring, including but not limited to 1) water quality of freshwater bodies, 2) forest disturbances, and 3) LCLUC. She also serves as an Envoy of the NASA-Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) InSAR (NISAR) mission, and she led the creation of the joint SERVIR-SilvaCarbon SAR Handbook on how to use SAR for forest monitoring and ecosystem applications. She is also a Ph.D. candidate in natural resource sciences at McGill University, specializing in SAR applications to improve forest monitoring.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/alfanderson.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/alfanderson.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Success Stories of Open Science Series: Fostering the next generation and adapting to local realities: Q&amp;amp;A with Dr. Reina Camacho Toro on open science practices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/reinatoro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success Stories of Open Science Series: Fostering the next generation and adapting to local realities: Q&amp;amp;A with Dr. Reina Camacho Toro on open science practices" /><published>2023-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/reinatoro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/reinatoro/">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Reina Camacho Toro is an experimental particle physicist and a member of the ATLAS collaboration at CERN. Her research revolves aroundanalyzing data to better understand the smallest components of matter, researching and developing instrumentation, developing science capacity-building programs to foster the next generation of scientists in Latin America, and strengthening collaborations between Europe and Latin America. Reina is part of a European-Latin American network creating postgraduate courses in advanced physics guided by the principles of open science and education at LA-CoNGA physics. LA-CoNGA physics was launched in 2020 and co-funded by the Erasmus+ program with the support of CERN, ICTP-UNESCO, and CNRS, among other scientific and industrial partners. She is also participating in the TOPS effort to build the OpenCore curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TOPS</name></author><summary type="html">Dr. Reina Camacho Toro is an experimental particle physicist and a member of the ATLAS collaboration at CERN. Her research revolves aroundanalyzing data to better understand the smallest components of matter, researching and developing instrumentation, developing science capacity-building programs to foster the next generation of scientists in Latin America, and strengthening collaborations between Europe and Latin America. Reina is part of a European-Latin American network creating postgraduate courses in advanced physics guided by the principles of open science and education at LA-CoNGA physics. LA-CoNGA physics was launched in 2020 and co-funded by the Erasmus+ program with the support of CERN, ICTP-UNESCO, and CNRS, among other scientific and industrial partners. She is also participating in the TOPS effort to build the OpenCore curriculum.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/reinatoro.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/TOPS-Website-Development/assets/img/posts/reinatoro.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>